Guide to the Ronald Magden Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Ronald Magden collection, Undated; 5185-002; 12.9 cubic feet 15 boxes
  - Longshore History
    - General
      - International Warehousemen's and Longshoremen's Union (ILWU)
        - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union-Pacific Maritime Association (ILWU-PMA) Healthcare Pamphlets and Brochures
          - Death, Accidental Death and Accidental Dismemberment Benefit Programs, Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - Hearing Aid Program, 1992 (Box-folder 7)
          - Non-Choice Port Plan, Hospital-Medical-Surgical Benefits (2 copies), 1989 (Box-folder 7)
          - Non-Choice Port Plan, Hospital-Medical-Surgical Benefits (2 copies), Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - Pension Plan, 1995 (Box-folder 7)
          - Supplemental Welfare Benefit Plan (2 copies), 1989 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan (2 copies), 1977 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, 1982 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, 1992 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan (3 copies), 1994 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan (2 copies), 1995 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan Brochure Folder, Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, Longshore Dental Programs, 1994 (Box-folder 7)
          - Welfare Plan, Longshore Dental Programs, 1999 (Box-folder 7)
      - Photographs
        - Motor Ship (M/S) Marie Bakke, 1926 (Box-folder 8/1)
        - Second Annual Convention of International Longshoremen OVERSIZE, 1939 (Box-folder 13/4)
        - Unidentified Speaker OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 13/5)
        - Waterfront, Union Members, Undated (Box-folder 8/3)
        - Waterfront, Union Members, Undated (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Publications
        - Pacific Coast Longshoreman Volume 1 OVERSIZE, 1935 (Box-folder 13/6)
        - Pacific Coast Longshoreman Volume 1 OVERSIZE, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 13/7)
        - Voice of the Federation,West Coast Sailors, Teamster's Bulletin, Pacific Coast Longshoremen, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 8/5)
        - The Dispatcher, 1972-1999 (Box-folder 8/6)
        - Pacific Maritime, Pacific Gateway, 1996, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 8/7)
        - The Anchor Light, 2006 (Box-folder 13/5)
      - Safety
        - Safety Research, 1929-1996 (Box-folder 8/8)
        - Safety Seminar Papers, 1994 (Box-folder 8/9)
        - Booklets
          - Longshoring Industry, OSHA Safety and Health Standards, 1975 (Box-folder 7)
          - Longshoring Industry, OSHA Safety and Health Standards (2 copies), 1985 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code, 1947 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (3 copies), 1949 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code, 1967 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (4 copies), 1979 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (4 copies), 1987 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (3 copies), 1990 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (3 copies), 1993 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code (3 copies), 1996 (Box-folder 7)
          - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code, 1999 (Box-folder 7)
          - Waterfront Safety, 1989 (Box-folder 7)
        - U.S. Department of Labor Brochures
          - "Dunnage", Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - "The Hatch Tender", Undated (Box-folder 7)
          - "Slips on Ships", Undated (Box-folder 7)
      - Strikes
        - 1934 Strike
          - Coroner’s Inquest: Deaths of Sperry and Bordoise, 1934 (Box-folder 8/10)
          - Article: “Seattle Longshoremen and the Great Maritime Strike of 1934” by Ronald Magden, Undated (Box-folder 8/11)
        - 1936/1937 Strike
          - Newspaper: The Tacoma Times, 1939 (Box-folder 8/12)
          - Radio Broadcast Transcripts: “Voice of the Maritime Unions”, 1936 (Box-folder 8/13)
          - Newspaper advertisement, 1937 (Box-folder 8/14)
          - Financial Records: Seattle Joint Strike Committee, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/15)
          - Bulletins
            - ILA Local 38-12 Northwest Joint Strike Committee; Letter to Dewey Bennett ILA Local 38-79; Joint Policy Committee; San Francisco ILA Women’s Voice; Pacific Coast Marine Firemen Oilers, Water-tenders and Wipers Association; ILA Local 38-82, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 8/16)
            - American Radio Telegraphists Association (ARTA), 1939 (Box-folder 8/17)
            - San Pedro Joint Strike Committee, 1936 (Box-folder 8/18)
            - Joint Strike Committee, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/19)
            - Vancouver, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/20)
            - Portland ILA Local 38-78 The Hook, 1939-1967 (Box-folder 8/21)
            - San Francisco ILA Local 38-79, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/22)
            - San Francisco Marine Cooks and Stewards Association of the Pacific Coast, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/23)
            - San Francisco Masters, Mates and Pilots of America Local 90, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/24)
            - West Coast Sailors, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/25)
            - Northwest Joint Strike Committee, 1937 (Box-folder 8/26)
            - American Student Union Appeal Against Strikebreaking, Undated (Box-folder 8/27)
          - Minutes
            - Joint Northwest Strike Committee (Part 1/2), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/28)
            - Joint Northwest Strike Committee (Part 2/2), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/29)
            - Portland Joint Strike Committee, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/30)
            - San Francisco Joint Policy Committee, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/31)
        - 1948 Strike
          - Correspondence, Bulletins, Clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 8/32)
          - Correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 8/33)
      - Waterfront Employer's Association (WEA): W.C. Dawson Ledgers
        - Finances, 1919-1935 (Box-folder 8/34)
        - Finances, 1923-1933 (Box-folder 8/35)
        - Finances, 1938-1945 (Box-folder 8/36)
        - Basic Agreements and Arbitration Awards, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 9/1)
        - Arbitration Awards, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 9/2)
        - Collective Reporting Data, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 9/3)
        - Quarterly Meeting, 1940 (Box-folder 9/4)
        - Quarterly Meeting, 1940 (Box-folder 9/5)
        - Quarterly Meeting, 1941 (Box-folder 9/6)
        - Annual Meeting, 1941 (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Washington Legislative League (WLL): W.C. Dawson
        - Notepad, Brief of Respondent, 1922,1948 (Box-folder 9/8)
        - Accounts Statement, 1928 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Bellingham
      - Disciplinary Notices, 1937 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - National Labor Relations Board
      - Resolution, Questionnaires, 1939 (Box-folder 9/11)
      - "United States of America Before the National Labor Relations Board Nineteenth Region, In the matter of Shipowners Association of the Pacific Coast, Waterfront Employer's Association of the Pacific Coast, Waterfront Employers of Washington, et al and International Longshoremen's Association Affiliated with the A.F. of L., Local No. 38-83, Local No. 38-86 and Local No. 38-97, Consolidated Cases No. XIX-R-568, No. XIX-R-569, No. XIX-R-570, Brief of Petitioners, John Geisness, L.B. Sulgrove, Attorneys for Petitioners" (3 copies), ca. 1940 (Box-folder 7)
      - San Francisco
        - Court Documents, 1941 (Box-folder 9/12)
        - Hearing Transcript, 1941 (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Seattle
        - List of Witnesses, Rebuttal, 1938 (Box-folder 9/14)
      - Tacoma
        - Memorandum, Court Documents, Washington Employers' Association Articles of Incorporation, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 9/15)
        - Correspondence, Court Documents, 1941 (Box-folder 9/16)
        - Witness Testimonies, 1941 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Port Angeles
      - Clippings: ILA OVERSIZE, 1941 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Portland
      - Correspondence, Minutes, Reports: Steam Schooners Arbitration, 1937 (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Untitled Manuscript re: Admission of African Americans to ILWU Local 8, Undated (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Port Townsend
      - Photograph: ILWU Members, Undated (Box-folder 9/20)
    - San Francisco
      - Minutes, Correspondence: Voices of the Federation Editorial Board, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Pamphlet: “Waterfront Writers and Artists”, 1980 (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Clippings: Longshoremen, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Student Paper: “The Great Awakening: A History of the 1919 San Francisco Riggers’ and Stevedores’ Strike” by Mary Joy Renfro, 1994 (Box-folder 9/24)
      - Jake Arnautoff
        - Work on the Waterfront: A Longshore Artist's View (3 copies), 1996 (Box-folder 9/25)
      - Herb Mills
        - Correspondence, Articles, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 9/26)
        - Speech: “The San Francisco Waterfront”, 1982 (Box-folder 9/27)
      - ILWU Local 10
        - Interview Transcript: Louis Goldblatt, 1978 (Box-folder 9/28)
        - Interview Transcript, Article, Memorial Service: George Benet, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 9/29)
    - Seattle
      - Minutes: Joint Executive Committee of Longshoremen and Truckers and Waterfront Employers, 1921-1933 (Box-folder 10/1)
      - National Longshore Board Hearings, 1934 (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Correspondence: Seattle Provisional Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1936 (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Honorable Withdrawal Cards: ILA Local 38-12, ILWU Local 19, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Metal Trades Council Papers: Member Roster, Miscellaneous Notes, 1948-1983 (Box-folder 10/5)
      - American Communications Association (ACA) 6
        - Correspondence, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Tom Ballard
        - Play Script: The New Tide, Undated (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Ray Fox
        - Manuscript: ILWU History, Undated (Box-folder 10/8)
      - ILA Local 38-12
        - Correspondence, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 10/9)
        - Letters, Member Roster, 1936 (Box-folder 10/10)
        - Correspondence, 1936 (Box-folder 10/11)
        - Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins, 1936 (Box-folder 10/12)
        - Correspondence: Simpson and Modesto Defense Funds, 1936 (Box-folder 10/13)
      - ILWU Local 19
        - Cemetery Records, 1917-1923 (Box-folder 10/14)
        - Clearance Committee Passes, 1948 (Box-folder 10/15)
        - Correspondence: Welfare, Insurance, Benefits, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 10/16)
        - Correspondence: Group Health, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 10/17)
        - Correspondence: Safety, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 10/18)
      - ILWU Local 52
        - Time Book: Supercargo-Supervisors, Checker's Association, 1974 (Box-folder 10/21)
      - Photographs
        - Seattle Joint Labor Relations Board, 1965 (Box-folder 10/22)
        - Waterfront, Union Members, Local 19 Dispatch Hall, Undated (Box-folder 10/23)
        - Waterfront, Union Members, Harry Bridges, Undated (Box-folder 10/24)
        - Waterfront, Union Members, 1934 Strike, Undated (Box-folder 10/25)
        - Negatives: Waterfront, International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union Local 19, Undated (Box-folder 10/26)
        - Waterfront Pier OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 13/10)
        - Waterfront Pier OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 13/11)
      - Harold E. Smith
        - Manuscript: “Working the Seattle Waterfront in 1935”, Undated (Box-folder 10/27)
      - Waterfront Employers of Washington
        - Correspondence, 1939 (Box-folder 10/28)
        - Correspondence, Minutes, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 10/29)
        - Minutes: Strike Policy Committee, 1948 (Box-folder 10/30)
        - Correspondence: Board of Trustees, 1951-1959 (Box-folder 10/31)
    - Tacoma
      - Articles of Incorporation: Tacoma Stevedores and Rigging Company, 1886, 2003 (Box-folder 10/32)
      - Notes, Clippings: Tacoma Central Labor Council, 1916-1990 (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Articles, Photographs: McLean Trucking Co., 1949 Longshore Accident, 1949-2006 (Box-folder 10/34)
      - Minutes: ILA/ILWU Women’s Auxiliaries, 1952-1986 (Box-folder 10/35)
      - Miscellaneous Papers, 1959, 1993 (Box-folder 10/36)
        Pamphlets: Labor Management Relations Act
        “Why Did the Tacoma Longshoremen Choose to Remain Outside the ILWU for Twenty Years?” by Ottilie Markholt
        Minutes
      - Area Wage Surveys, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 10/37)
      - Speeches, Presentation, Magazine: Port of Tacoma, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 10/38)
      - Papers, Ephemera: Spaghetti Extravaganza, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 10/39)
      - Manuscript: Tacoma Labor History, Undated (Box-folder 10/40)
      - List: Union Member Nicknames, Undated (Box-folder 10/41)
      - Clippings
        - Longshore Baseball, 1938 (Box-folder 10/42)
        - Longshoremen, 1897-2004 (Box-folder 10/43)
        - Tacoma News Tribune, The Daily Ledger, Seattle Post Intelligencer OVERSIZE, Pre-1900 (Box-folder 13/12)
        - Tacoma Sunday Ledger, The Daily Ledger, Seattle Daily Post Intelligencer OVERSIZE, Pre-1900 (bulk), 1954 (Box-folder 14/1)
        - Tacoma News Tribune, The Daily Ledger, Pacific Northwest Quarterly OVERSIZE, 1899-2002 (Box-folder 14/2)
        - The Daily Ledger OVERSIZE, 1900-1917 (Box-folder 14/3)
        - Tacoma News Tribune, The Tacoma Sunday Ledger, Tacoma Labor Advocate OVERSIZE, 1918-1934 (Box-folder 14/4)
        - Tacoma News Tribune, Seattle Daily Times OVERSIZE, 1934 (Box-folder 14/5)
        - Tacoma News Tribune, Tacoma Labor Advocate OVERSIZE, 1935-1978 (Box-folder 15/1)
        - Port of Tacoma:The Daily Ledger, Tacoma News Tribune, The Tacoma Times, The West Coast Trade OVERSIZE, 1892-1906 (Box-folder 15/2)
        - Port of Tacoma:The Daily Ledger, Tacoma News Tribune, The Tacoma Times, The West Coast Trade OVERSIZE, 1908-1989 (Box-folder 15/3)
      - International Longshoremen's Association (ILA)
        - Newspaper: ILA Longshoreman, 1937 (Box-folder 11/1)
        - Report: Timberworkers, 1937 (Box-folder 11/2)
        - Correspondence, Bulletins, Arbitration Documents, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 11/3)
        - Minutes: Executive Board Meetings, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 11/4)
        - Minutes: Executive Board Meetings, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - List: Registered Tacoma Members Locals 38-97, 38-83, 38-86, 1950 (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Microfilm Index: Tacoma Public Library, 1970 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU) Local 23
        - Papers from ILWU Archives, 1937-1952 (Box-folder 11/8)
        - Papers from ILWU Archives, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 11/9)
        - Interview Transcripts: Philip Lelli, Marlene Anderson, Morris Thoreson, Harold Anderson, Thomas Anderson, John Now, 1980-1992 (Box-folder 11/10)
        - Newspapers, Correspondence, Ephemera: Centennial Celebration, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 11/11)
        - Booklet, Photographs: Centennial Celebration, 1986 (Box-folder 11/12)
        - Interview Transcript: Art Martinson, Nick Engels, Bill Roberts, 1986 (Box-folder 11/13)
        - Exhibit Guide: “Longshore Legacy”, 1991 (Box-folder 11/14)
        - Interview Transcripts: Lee Barker, Lawrence Killeen, Robert Early, Richard Dale Smith, James Cook, 1992 (Box-folder 11/15)
        - Obituaries, Eulogies, 2004 (Box-folder 11/16)
        - Program: “A Tribute: Remembering Ottilie Markholt”, 2005 (Box-folder 11/17)
        - Article: Harry Hilliard (by Ronald Magden), 2006 (Box-folder 11/18)
        - Manuscript: Tacoma Longshore History, Undated (Box-folder 11/19)
      - Philip Lelli
        - Personal Papers, 1913-1995 (Box-folder 11/20)
        - Writings, 1983 (Box-folder 11/21)
        - Articles, Speeches, 1987 (Box-folder 11/22)
      - Photographs
      - Ship with New Zealand wool, 1962 (Box-folder 11/23)
      - Waterfront, Unions, ILWU 23 Picnic, Undated (Box-folder 11/24)
      - Waterfront. Port of Tacoma, Undated (Box-folder 11/25)
      - Waterfront, Union Members, Undated (Box-folder 11/26)
      - Waterfront (includes some slides), Undated (Box-folder 11/27)
      - Gayle Rieber Proofs: Waterfront, ILWU 23 Members, Undated (Box-folder 11/28)
      - Union Gatherings, ILWU 23, Undated (Box-folder 11/29)
      - Waterfront, Union Gatherings, ILWU 23, Undated (Box-folder 11/30)
      - Waterfront, Union Gatherings, ILA, ILWU 23, Undated (Box-folder 11/31)
      - Waterfront, Union Members, Undated (Box-folder 11/32)
      - Union Members, Undated (Box-folder 11/33)
      - Artwork, Union Members, Aerial Views of Tacoma OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Waterfront, Union Members OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Waterfront OVERSIZE, Undated (Box-folder 15/6)
      - Publications
        - Newspaper: The Tacoma Times-Tacoma Port Edition, 1938 (Box-folder 11/34)
        - Book: To Live in Dignity: Pierce County Labor, 1883-1989 (Box-folder 11/35)
      - Tiny Thronson
        - Correspondence, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 11/36)
      - Waterfront Employers of Washington (WEW)
        - Minutes, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 11/37)
        - Minutes: Luncheon Meeting, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 11/38)
        - Correspondence: Non-Members, 1935 (Box-folder 11/39)
        - Records, Correspondence: Finances, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 11/30)
        - Records, Correspondence: Finances, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 11/31)
        - Correspondence, 1948-1960 (Box-folder 12/1)
        - Harbor Commerce Booklet, Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box-folder 12/2)
        - Interview Transcript: Elizabeth Dawson, 1990 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Vancouver
      - Report: Waterfront Trouble, 1935 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Tacoma History
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1918-1983 (Box-folder 12/5)
      Tacoma Daily News Article “Want to have colored men organized,” 1918; Tacoma Transportation Timeline; Important dates in Tacoma History, Letters; Northern Pacific Labor Agency; Hotel Carlton, 1921
    - Album: Tacoma Fire Department Personnel, 1938 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Newspaper: Tacoma News Tribune, 1939 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Publications: Labor Relations in Tacoma, Major Employers of Pierce County, Workers Compensation Laws, 1975-1999 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Writings of Others: Chapter 5: “On the Waterfront” by Caroline Gallacci, 1998 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Teamster History
    - Court Decisions complied by Western Conference of Teamsters Legal Research Department, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Publications, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Incoming Mailings: Gary Reese, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Washington State Labor Documents
    - Labor Market Information Reviews, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Labor Market Information Reviews, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Labor Market Information Reviews, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Tacoma
      - Manager/Supervisor Manual, Employee Assistance Program, WA Public Employees Collective Bargaining Act, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12/16)
      - Affirmative Action Report, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 12/17)
- Ronald Magden collection, 1930-2003; 1971-2003; 5185-003; 2 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Research materials for Magden's books on Japanese-Americans living in the Pacific Northwest, particularly for his book, Furusato: Tacoma-Pierce County Japanese 1888-1988.
  Open to all users.
  The following book was separated from the collection and catalogued: Ō-Ka Nikkei shimin shashinchō: narabi ni Eibun Nihon jijō taikan / [hensansha Kawai Sōsuke].
- Ronald Magden collection, circa 1983-1990; 5185-004; 2.76 cubic feet 5 boxes
  Audiocassettes and videotape interviews with longshoremen and teamsters primarily for his books The Working Longshoreman and A History of Seattle Waterfront Workers. The records relate especially to the activities of longshore workers and of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters on the West Coast and in the Puget sound region.
  Also among these papers is a typed manuscript by Ottilie Markholt entitled: Against the Current: A Social Memoir along with Ottilie Markholt's handwritten notes on longshore history (n.d.)
  View selections from this collection in digital format.
  Access restricted: For terms of access contact Special Collections.
  - Against the Current: A Social Memoir by Ottilie Markholt (Box 1)
  - Ottilie Markholt's notes on Longshore history (Box 2)
  - Video recordings
    - Videotapes labeled as already digitized (Box 3)
    - DVDs--most likely the digitized versions of the above videotapes (Box 3)
  - Audio cassettes with the note: digitize, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Tapes numbered 1-88 and noted as: to be digitized, ca. 1983-1987 (Box 5)
    - Tapes numbered 89-159, ca. 1983-1987 (Box 5)